<introduction title="The Dialectal Strategy">
  <cover src="dialekt.jpg" resolution="240dpi" />
  <subtitle>Accurate large-scale translation for the small languages of the World</subtitle>
</introduction>
<section title="Faith Cometh By Hearing the Word of God">
  <chapter>
    <line>Given the importance of translating all of the Scriptures accurately into all of the languages</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>And the sheer size of the Scriptures in their entirety</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>We conclude that translations should target hypothetical “average” languages; hypothetical kiones</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
</section>
<section title="The Words and the Word">
  <chapter>
    <line>W. V. O. Quine’s ”indeterminacy of meaning” essentially reveals the centrally-crucial role of faith in all cross-cultural communication</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>Armed with the creeds—with faith—we know what doctrine rises off the pages of Scripture, no matter what the language; we know the Message of the messages, and the Word of whom the words speak</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
</section>
<section title="Hypothetical Koines and Liturgical Languages">
  <chapter>
    <line>Hypothetical koines are either inevitable in making the translation, or necessarily consequent (non-hypothetical) after a translation</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>Conscious hypothetical koines are more-preferable, and they may contain intentional borrowings (such as Hebraisms and Hellenisms) to preserve accuracy and nuance; liturgical languages are the commonest example (e.g.; KJV English for many of us today)</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
</section>
<section title="The Dialectal Strategy">
  <chapter>
    <line>The dialectal strategy: noun borrowings</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>The dialectal strategy: consistent verb forms</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>The dialectal strategy: verb borrowings</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>The dialectal strategy: finding or creating a pivot language</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
</section>
<section title="Dialectal Language Tools">
  <chapter>
    <line>Using the LXX to establish Judeo-Hellenic usage patterns of NT Koine Greek</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>Exploiting modern typesetting to create dialectal translations (footnotes, columnar layouts)</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <line>Translations that contain dialect guides (generated dictionaries)</line>
    <discussion>
    </discussion>
  </chapter>
</section>
